Curriculum vitae



Arvind Kumar

Mobile No.7325082202

E-mail: arvindkr672@gmail.com



Career Objectives:

6 years' experience with extensive subject matter expertise in IT Service Management (ITSM) and ITIL methods, in information technology, incident management, technical Support, infrastructure management, Location End User Support, Remote Support, Email, & chat, good communication skills and ready to work both independently and as a member of a team, utilizing the skills acquired during my course and experience.

Work Experience:

Organization :- CMS IT SERVICES PVT.LTD

Duration :- (Dec, 2022 to till date.) **Designation** :- Wintel & G-Suite Admin

Job Responsibilities:

- SCCM 2007 & 2012 & 2016 Server Manage patch management And Client machine installed.
- Knowledge of enterprise Windows Server roles including Active Directory Services, DNS, Group Policy, DHCP, RIS,
- Perform routine software updates to enhance functionalities and security.
- Good knowledge of any System Center Products (SCCM), with an emphasis on the following Configuration Manager concepts.
- Application support such as Adobe creative suite, Microsoft office 2007, 2010, 2016, o365. Package. Maintain workstation security using various technologies such as endpoint protection software, data. Encryptions, application white listing, and others.
- user NTID, Creation, mail migration, G-Drive owner ship transfer, mail storage increase, server patching WSUS,DL Group Creation. IBM san switch, Hardware storage. Dell Server installation & Configuration.
- · Upgrade and Maintain VMWare ESX.
- · Work and major severity and complex server issues.
- Backup and restore VMWare servers and virtual sessions.
- RCA preparation and meeting SLA for RCA submission.
- Planning and implementing fixes / Patches
- Performance and capacity management on VMWare servers.

Work Experience:

Organization :- Vinsak India Pvt. Ltd.

Designation :- IT Executive

Duration :- (21March, 2022 to December, 2022)

Job Responsibilities:

- Experience of implementing, configuring, Monitoring, and Manage Network equipment Basic L2 Switch/Firewall/Router/ Configuration and troubleshooting.
- SAP B1, Gathering customer requirements and conducting gap analysis. Performing system Configuration installation data migration and testing Conducting and support.

Work Experience:

Organization :- Alchemy Techsol India Pvt. Ltd.

Designation :- Technical Team Leader

Duration :- 23rd Feb, 2021 to March, 2022

Job Responsibilities:

- Experience of implementing, configuring, Monitoring, Managing, and troubleshooting such as DLP like Encryption, Bit locker, EDR, EPM, Fire Eye, Cisco Any Connect, Titus, Antivirus Symantec Endpoint protection. VPN, Modem, Network, firewall.
- Support systems deployment, configuration management and application installations. Knowledge of hardware and software installation, testing and operation.
- ITIL Ticketing tools Such As BMC Remedy IT Service Management, CRM, End User Support International. over the phone, chat, Email and remote support.
- Ensure all customer requests, queries, are recorded accurately and assigned to the relevant workgroup within the service management tool.
- Ensure on-time escalation of P1, P2, incident to L2/L3 teams and follow-up until resolution.
- Produce reports and validation of SLA adherence on availability, system performance, problem tracking etc.
- Resolved all change Orders, Incidents and major incidents within SLA and updated with proper resolution.
- Call Management Logging categorizing, allocating, follow-up, update user, Closure, resolution in ticket logging tool. Respond to IT incident and Request received Remedy Tickets.

Work Experience:

Organization :- JKC TOTAL IT SOSUTION
Designation :- SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR
(August, 2019 to October, 2020)

Job Responsibilities:

- Analyzes system faults and troubleshoots and runs diagnostic tests on operating systems and hardware to detect and resolve problems.
- Reviews and prepares documentation for systems, tests and installation of windows based software. Investigates and selects methods and techniques for obtaining solutions .
- Responsible for preventive maintenance on Windows operating systems as well as repair to System/environmental problems
- Experience troubleshooting networking connectivity issues, printer, servers, and applications to meet Business needs
- Provide support for the following: PC security, networking, PC hardware, Windows 7, Windows Server 2008, Active Directory, group policies. Monitor, maintain and inventory network infrastructure, network Systems, and components, system admin and desktop systems with associated peripheral equipment.
- Apply patches, updates, and upgrades to servers, workstations and stored images. Perform network scans as requested or required .
- Implement and support infrastructure solutions in sophisticated, high-performance trading Environments that demand stability, tremendous throughput and low latency.

Work Experience:

Organization :- Abdul Raheman Al-Otaishan.K.S.A
Designation :- SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Duration :- Feb, 2016 to May, 2018.

Job Responsibilities:

- Good problem-solving skills, open-mindness, willing to explore new technologies.
- Demonstrated experience working in an IT environment (e.g. desktop, operating systems, cloud, Infrastructure.
- Deal with management, vendors, and others effectively in situations requiring tact and discretion while working through difficult issues.
- Anyof the following skills would be a distinct advantage. Connecting video conference webcasting.

- Ensure daily operational activities are completed within time line. Update customer on delays.
- ☐ Maintain Asset data, Documenting Asset data and adding/updating new configuration items to asset data, in CMBD
- Network connectivity troubleshooting, ping, Tracert, telnet, ipconfig, Netstat, Arp. Investigating, Diagnosing and resolving network related problems. Configuring SCCM client.
- Manage window network user, computers, printers, etc. with Active Directory.
- Escalating and communicating the status of major incidents and problems with project management.
- Call escalation as per defined escalation matrix. Configured and support Microsoft outlook.
- Provide communication to user through email or Notification about the status of tickets.:

Qualification:

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

- B.A HONS (HISTORY) from B.R Ambedkar Muzaffarpur University, Year-2011.
- I.Sc From B.S.E.B Patna, Year-2007.
- Matriculation From B.S.E.B Patna, Year-2005.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

• ADHN & Information Security from CMS, Delhi. Year-2011.

TECHNICAL CERTIFICATION

- MCSA (Microsoft Certified System Administrator)
- CMS Certified Network Specialist

MANAGEMENT

• Experience of ITIL incident, problem and change management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Operating system: XP, Win7, win 8.1, window 10, Windows 11,

Server Operating system: window server 2016, 2012r2, 2008r2, 2003, configuration and administrationDNS, DHCP,Group Policies, Active Directory, Backup and restore, Citrix, VMware, windows backup.

- Set-up of a VMWare High availability (HA) cluster.
- Proven experience in ESX Server Installation
- Configuration of virtual switches, network connections and port groups Configure Storage
- Support OS monitoring Client Software, Backup and Recovery client, Client Software, automated Security, health checking client os monitoring
- Security in a VMWare Virtualized Environment
- Additional :- Preferable to have VMWare Certification.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS:

- Analytical skill, fast-learner, team oriented, flexible with good communication skills
- Excellent interpersonal and customer service skills and the ability to effectively collaborate with other IT professionals outside of the work center
- · Strong listening, written, verbal and telephone communication skills
- Demonstrated problem analysis and critical thinking skills
- Skills and experience in problem determination, analysis and resolution

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Name	: Arvind Kumar
Father's name	: Chandrika Sharma
D.O.B.	: 13 th June, 1990.

Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Indian
Passport : Yes

Linguistic Skills : English & Hindi

HOBBIES:

Book Reading & Listening Music.

Date :/	
Place :	(Arvind Kumar)